It feels great! Come on down!
Go on, she's calling you.
No she's not.
Yes, she is.
See? She's looking at you.
Buzz off, will you?
Aw, he beat you to the punch.
Yay!
This is dumb.
Huh?
This is only fun for people whose sense of danger is dulled.
It's not as though anything changes once you jump.
Yeah, this is the sort of thing that I—
Just jump already!
Oh, crap!
For the love of...
Wait.
No, this is gonna be bad.
Huh?
What was that?
That was our world, wasn't it?
Then did we just go home?
You're amazing, you know that?
Your talents can achieve anything.
I wouldn't go that far.
This just comes in handy, is all—
it's not the kind of power that changes the world.
Don't you think?
Still, this world's so unfair, isn't it?
There's someone on this island who doesn't need to compensate the others.
There are definitely those in the world
who are chosen to get special treatment.
How's the plan coming along?
Oh, yeah...
Things are starting to come together,
but some key elements still remain unclear.
It'll be fine.
Someone will eventually show up to save us.
Mm, this is good!
Too spicy.
Hey, pass the water.
You know,
we could probably get back home with his power, couldn't we?
We made it home earlier for a moment.
But I'm not even sure if it is my power.
Why not? You gotta take responsibility for your actions.
You did that thing, didn't you?
What do you call it, warping?
Even Rajdhani says so. Go on, do it.
I really don't know if it was me.
It doesn't feel like I did anything.
Ugh, man, you really are useless.
You're seriously dragging everyone down.
Pull it together, asshole.
Then again, was that really our world?
Hmm, I'm not sure.
It wasn't actually the "light," for the record.
Should we have Rajdhani look into it tomorrow?
That monkey...
Special delivery!
Hey, having dinner together?
He's still pissed.
I said I was sorry, but he just can't seem to let it go.
Such a child.
Is carrying that stuff here your job?
Just use your power. What is it?
Oh, it's not some fancy kind of power.
Yeah... I'd rather not say what it is.
Oh hey, Nagara,
wanna play a little baseball together again sometime?
Huh? Where's this coming from?
I have to practice once in a while, or I'll get rusty.
Come on, join me.
Wow, this is a surprise. You were in the baseball club?
I don't remember.
Are you for real? I'll never forget it!
During our last tournament,
your three consecutive errors cost us the game!
I-Is that right?
If it weren't for that, we could have gone to Nationals!
Hey, you okay?
Ace is around, right?
Why don't you play with him?
No can do. You know how much he hates to practice.
Besides, lately he's been too busy with his girlfriend.
Oh yeah, her.
Must be nice to be popular.
Hey, any of you heard what Ace's power is?
I haven't.
What is it?
Apparently it's "Sweetwater."
Huh? What does that do?
Exactly that.
Supposedly, he can make any water drinkable.
What a riot!
For all that big talk, he gets to drink muddy water and say it's yummy.
Say, if you're asking for baseball practice,
does that mean you have a place where you can play?
As a matter of fact,
I made a baseball diamond not far from here.
Whoa, did you?
Yeah.
That's amazing.
Huh? What's that, monkeys?
That was awesome, transfer kid!
Huh?
Nobody's beaten the Rock Monster since Steroid!
Huh? Who's that?
Steroid Monkey!
Eight-time record-setter for
home runs in the Monkey League!
Wait, what's the Monkey League?
Huh? You don't know?!
Oh, right, you can't see them, huh? Sorry 'bout that.
The Monkey League—
It's a baseball league here in the world of Monkey Mountain,
played by the great monkeys,
which started when the first ball and bat
and the rules of the game were handed down to them.
In the Monkey League, a number of great players arose from among the nameless masses,
who all bore the same appearances.
The legendary home run king,
who hit an unprecedented, record-breaking 80 home runs in one year, Steroid Monkey!
Toppling the god of batting,
Monkey River's career batting average
by two thousandths,
the miracle hitting machine, Upper Monkey!
The greatest catcher of the Bigfoot era, Mister Monkey,
who as a manager would go on to break the record for most league wins,
with a legendary ten-season-long streak!
Then came the golden age of the M-League.
A miracle monkey came along and dethroned those previous legends one by one.
The monster, Monkey Blue!
This maverick of the league was the only one with blue hair,
who, despite weathering ugly
discrimination and crafty persecution,
triumphed with overwhelming talent,
to ultimately become a hero,
and a symbol of hope for the monkeys!
Despite being a rookie,
Blue put the brakes to the king, Steroid Monkey!
Breaking his bat along with his heart,
Blue drove him to retirement.
Then, with his mighty pitching arm, Blue led his underdog team Monkey and Club to victory,
preventing Bigfoot's championship streak from reaching 11.
The public accepted this new hair color,
and there was no doubt in anybody's mind
that the era of Monkey Blue had begun!
But then...
a great tragedy shook the sport,
when a near-perfect game was foiled,
and a monkey was killed in the diamond!
I wanna see them! I wanna see the monkeys!
Huh? That's your takeaway?
I want to see the monkeys, too!
I know, right? Monkeys! Monkeys!
I want my own pet monkey!
Where can we see them?
Right here.
Huh? Where?
Like I said, here.
Uh, here?
Yeah.
Right here.
But it's not like you can just wait around and see them.
You need to use a certain piece of gear.
Gear?
What kind of gear?
Oh, the monkeys?
That's right. You have to use one of these to see the monkeys.
A Monkey Getter. Wanna borrow it?
Yeah!
[No! No way in hell!]
Hey, if money's the problem, I got you covered. See?
It's not about the money. She just doesn't like you.
Damn her. If we had that thing,
we could see the monkeys!
What do we do? Steal it?
Threaten them? Beat them? Trick them?
Take it easy.
So what do we do?
Hey, how do you all even know about the monkeys in the first place?
We were helping Cap with some baseball practice,
and he told us about them.
But...
Yeah?
Can you really see monkeys with that thing?
Huh? You don't believe me?
N-No, it's not that.
I get what you mean, though.
It just looks like a regular flashlight, doesn't it?
But if you shine it on yourself like this,
you become able to see the monkeys.
Or maybe more precisely,
the world where the monkeys live.
Oh.
Then again, Nagara, for you, why not?
Yeah, for old time's sake, as former teammates.
You'll lend it to him?
How does this sound?
You've already got some practice in.
Play against me, and if you win, I'll let you borrow it.
A one-inning game.
If any of you get a hit off one of my pitches, you win.
What do you say?
Not a chance.
We'll play your game!
Heh, that's more like it.
But I'm not playing for nothing.
I want something in return.
If you lose...
Huh? Hey, I don't know about that...
It's settled!
Come on, you're not even close!
Stop dropping your elbow! Keep your head up!
I've got no hope of hitting against him.
Well, you could be right.
Is Ace really that good?
Yeah, he's a prodigy.
He's already had pros come asking about him.
Oh, yeah? That is good.
Hey!
What good is it if you're beaten before you even play?!
Play to win! If you don't believe in yourself, who will?!
I've never counted on myself for anything.
I can't...
Well, you never know what's going to happen during a game.
Hope for a miracle and do your best.
By the way, what was his condition for doing this?
Oh, nothing that important.
You're not playing baseball with them?
They'd have it in the bag with you there.
I'm not interested in seeing monkeys.
Plus that oaf is there.
I'm terribly curious about this
mysterious flashlight, the Monkey Getter.
If something like that exists,
it could change my whole view of the world!
Makes no difference to me.
Once Nagara masters his power,
we'll be home in no time.
I don't think it's quite that simple.
That year had been Blue's greatest season.
Every game, he pitched the full nine innings and won.
With a league-high 32 wins posted,
the team won its second consecutive title.
Then, in the final game of the season,
Blue was closing in on pitching an absolutely perfect game!
It was 16-0,
with Monkey and Club commanding a huge lead going into the final inning.
Bottom of the 9th, two outs.
Blue had struck out 26 batters on 80 pitches,
and had gotten the last batter two strikes down in quick order!
The overflowing stadium was blanketed in electricity,
waiting for the call of that last pitch to ring out!
All of the monkeys there focused their intense gaze on Blue's every move!
None of them had any doubt that this would be an absolutely perfect game!
Yes, there was indeed an uneasy foreboding.
In hindsight, it was clear.
One monkey, unaccustomed to that pressure—
the peculiar umpire...
Then, the world went off-kilter.
The 81st pitch! Out of respect for Blue's honor,
I will say that it was by no means a careless pitch.
The world itself had slipped!
No, there is no possibility that I'm being partial to Blue!
It actually happened!
The world itself moved just a little bit! It's the truth!
The ball looked like it may have slightly missed the strike zone,
but could be called as either a strike or a ball!
And the umpire making the call was the one monkey in that stadium—
in that whole world—who did slip with the world!
The crowd rose to their feet en masse!
They started tearing out their hair,
and stamping their feet with all their might!
They broke out in boos! Tremendous booing!
The umpire firmly refused requests to check the video replay.
Blue was visibly dissatisfied, and charged the umpire!
"That was a strike!"
The umpire quietly shook his head.
"Hey, are you nuts?!
That pitch would have sealed an absolutely perfect game!"
The umpire firmly replied, "I am aware."
"No, you don't get it!
Why didn't you call that ball a strike?!
The outcome of the game is already decided!
On top of that, this game is a throwaway anyhow!
The batter is dispirited!
So how come, when it didn't matter if you called that pitch a strike or a ball,
did you not call it a strike?!
What was the point of that?!
Moreover, do you not hear the cheers of hope and anticipation from the crowd?!
You know that this isn't the outcome they wanted!"
"I am aware of that, as well."
So, why did he?
"The hopes of the crowd have no bearing on this game.
There is a stadium here, and inside it, there are rules.
No matter what the reasons may be, things should remain fair in here."
"You're wrong!
This is a baseball show!
Everyone is pinning their hopes and dreams on me!
I'm carrying the weight of the whole Monkey League!
Right now, as far as this place goes, I am the rules!
Now, reverse your decision!"
Blue's huge hands were trembling.
"I cannot do that."
The umpire was utterly unflinching.
"Right now, as far as this place is concerned, I am the rules."
Blue knew the truth as well.
The replay was shown on the big screen.
The fact was, due to the world slipping,
the ball had missed the strike zone by no more than a micron!
But Blue could not accept that decision.
When play resumed,
Blue threw the ball at the exact same speed,
on the exact same course as that 81st pitch,
three more times.
"Ball four!"
Spiking his glove into the mound, Blue walked off the game.
This incited the stirred-up spectators to begin rioting!
As the crowd rushed onto the field, they all charged at the umpire!
As the terrified batter looked on,
the umpire had his head beaten in,
and the rioting crowd tore him apart.
His thin, scruffy body had its flesh and blood trodden on,
spat upon, dishonored, and breathed its last.
The monkey died.
All over a game of baseball.
Blue had taken on all of their hopes for that one pitch.
What an amazing monkey.
That's for sure. Blue was the best pitcher ever.
No, I meant the umpire.
Huh?
He prevailed against the whole world.
You're making too much of it.
Nagara, don't you feel anything?
Don't you feel angry?
I don't know.
Strike! Batter out!
It makes sense that that monkey got killed.
A world where the ordinary kill the genius,
or where ignorant fools destroy talent is...
Foul!
With that rugged, yet beautiful form,
she'll never even see my lightning fastball.
Strike two!
Strike! Batter out!
Good luck.
Strike!
Strike two!
So, how do you like my pitching?
Yeah, you're really good.
I doubt there's any way I can hit that.
You just don't feel like hitting.
There's no way I could.
Why am I not...
B-Ball!
Hey, watch out!
Yeah, yeah! That was a beanball! Eject him!
He is so lame!
He is handsome, though.
Hey, you okay?
I'm the one who gave baseball to the monkeys.
I am special.
If you lose,
then you return us to our world as soon as possible.
You can't tell me you can't do it, either.
I heard. You're our "savior", right?
Huh? No, I'm not—
Just looking at you now makes me want to puke.
I can't believe someone like you got chosen.
This world is all messed up.
Put us back in the world where I am properly appreciated.
That's what your power is for.
I don't know if I can.
Do it. Even if it kills you.
Huh? A m-monkey?
A one-armed monkey...
How did you know he had one arm?
Can you see the umpire?
The truth is, you wanted to be a baseball player, too, didn't you?
But you couldn't.
Still, you were drawn to the sometimes cruel fairness of baseball,
and became an umpire.
You were watching over the game from there, this whole time.
It wasn't the umpire that got killed...
Huh?
It was baseball!
Huh? What are you talking—
I saw it myself.
So he can do it.
You scum.
Don't get so full of yourself.
That's it.
Go!
Strike! Batter out!
Ah, you idiot!
That was awesome, Nagara!
I underestimated you.
Too bad. But that was a nice swing.
Thanks.
Aw, we don't get to see any monkeys.
Here.
Thanks.
Huh? You've got something stuck to you.
What is it?
What is this?
That didn't come from my cats.
Is it some kind of fur?
When did it get stuck to you?
You're here to cheer me up?
[This isn't where we're supposed to be.]
I guess today's the last day of life on the island.
I'm going to miss it.
R-Right...
Actually, I've been thinking of quitting baseball for a while now.
Nobody knows better than me that
I lack the talent to play in the big leagues.
Still, we played for the fun of it a long time ago. Just like monkeys.
But before we knew it,
it became about whether or not we had the talent,
or how it would get us into college,
and that started taking up all our attention.
But then, watching those monkeys playing,
I couldn't sit still.
I don't know how to say it, but it was kind of like...
I felt like, "I wanna play baseball!"
And once I realized that, here it was—
the diamond was already in place.
Strange, isn't it? I don't have the talent for baseball,
but it's all I ever think about.
That's not so strange.
It's not?
Yeah.
Well?
Does the plan seem like it's going to work?
Who knows? But it sure is an amazing power.
We can go anywhere.
Really? It doesn't look that way to me...
She's not lying...
but it also may not be exactly what everyone is thinking, either.
Nagara has reached the point where he can control his warp power.
We can say goodbye to this place now.
Okay, let's go home to our own world!
Go on, do it.
All right.
Huh? Where are we?
Oh, this isn't right.
This isn't it, either.
Where's the school, already?
How long until we get there?
That's enough showing off.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
I can't go back.
Huh?!
Not just to our world.
I can't go where I want to.
That guy really is worthless.
Aww, are you serious?
Well, that sucked.
It's our fault for expecting anything.
That's about what I figured.
That pretty well clears that up.
Nagara has the power to move to other worlds.
But he can't choose where he goes.
I mean, I can't believe this world we've been in is one that he would choose.
Hey, look over there.
Huh? M-Ms. Aki?!
A teacher?
Someone else besides us got cast away?!
She's here to save us!
Shut up, you worms!
Playtime's over.